Prentiss Taylor
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Prentiss Taylor papers
1885-1991
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Prentiss Taylor
20.4 linear feet
The collection measures 20.4 linear feet, dates from 1885 to 1991 (bulk dates 1908-1986) and documents the career of Harlem Renaissance lithographer, teacher, and painter Prentiss Taylor. The collection consists primarily of subject/correspondence files (circa 16 ft.), reflecting Prentiss' career as a lithographer and painter, his association with figures prominent in the Harlem Renaissance, notably Carl Van Vechten and Langston Hughes, his activities as president of the Society of Washington Printmakers and other art organizations, his work in art therapy treating mental illness, and his teaching position at American University. The subject files contain mostly correspondence, but many include photographs and printed material. Also included are biographical, financial, legal and printed material; several hundred photographs; notes and writings; sketchbooks, drawings and a few prints by Taylor; and scrapbooks dating from 1885-1956.
Biographical Note
Prentiss Taylor was born in 1907 at the Washington, D. C. residence of his maternal grandmother, his birth assisted by his grandmother's cook, affectionately known as Cookie Belle.
In the 1920s, Taylor studied painting with Charles W. Hawthorne in Provincetown, but turned to lithography in the late 1920s to early 1930s during his enrollment at the Art Students League in New York City. He received further training in that medium at the George C. Miller workshop in New York. During this period, he also designed costumes for the American-Oriental Revue. Taylor worked primarily in the printmaking medium for the rest of his life, experimenting with various techniques and compositions and ultimately achieving a status as one this country's great lithographers. Taylor depicted mostly realistic and narrative scenes of subjects and themes that reflected his personal interests in music, architecture, religion and social justice.
During his time in New York, Taylor developed close friendships with poet Langston Hughes and writer Carl Van Vechten. He collaborated with Hughes in the formation of the Golden Stair Press to produce publications reflecting the ideas of the Harlem Renaissance. Taylor created a number of prints and illustration for the press and its publications.
After returning to Washington, D.C., Taylor's work was included in exhibitions at the Corcoran Gallery, the Smithsonian Institution, the Baltimore Museum of Art and the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts in Richmond. He was represented by the Franz Bader Gallery in Washington, D.C., and by the Bethesda Art Gallery in Maryland. In 1942, Taylor was elected President of the Society of Washington Printmakers, a position he held for thirty-four years. He also worked as an art therapist for more than thirty years and taught oil painting at American University from 1955-1975.
Prentiss Taylor died October 7, 1991 in Washington, D.C.
Scope and Content Note
The collection measures 20.4 linear feet, dates from 1885 to 1991 (bulk dates 1908-1986) and documents the career of Harlem Renaissance lithographer, teacher, and painter Prentiss Taylor. The collection consists primarily of subject/correspondence files (circa 16 ft.), reflecting Prentiss' career as a lithographer and painter, his association with figures prominent in the Harlem Renaissance, notably Carl Van Vechten and Langston Hughes, his activities as president of the Society of Washington Printmakers and other art organizations, his work in art therapy treating mental illness, and his teaching position at American University. The subject files contain mostly correspondence, but many include photographs and printed material. Also included are biographical, financial, legal and printed material; several hundred photographs; notes and writings; sketchbooks, drawings and a few prints by Taylor; and scrapbooks dating from 1885-1956.
The Langston Hughes files contain photocopies of letters from Hughes, greeting cards, ten original photographs of Hughes, and an autographed card printed with Hughes' poem, The Negro Speaks of Rivers. In addition, there is a contract between Hughes and Taylor, witnessed by Carl Van Vechten, forming the Golden Stair Press, through which many of Hughes' poems were printed with illustrations by Taylor. A rare edition of their first publication, The Negro Mother, is found here. Also found in this file is a 1932 final copy of Scottsboro Limited, another collaborative effort between Taylor and Hughes that focused on a case where nine black youths were falsely accused of raping two white women. The collection contains extensive correspondence about Taylor's lithograph of the same title and the printing of the publication. Other rare Harlem Renaissance publications found within Taylor's papers include Golden Stair Broadsides, Opportunity Journal of Negro Life, The Rebel Poet, and Eight Who Lie in the Death House, several of which were also illustrated by Taylor.
Prentiss Taylor's long association with Langston Hughes and other figures of the Harlem Renaissance stemmed from his early friendship with Carl Van Vechten. Taylor's papers contain correspondence with Van Vechten, autographed copies of Van Vechten's booklets, and numerous photographs of notable Harlem Renaissance figures, many taken by Van Vechten, including Zora Neale Hurston, Bill "Bojangles" Robinson, Eugene O'Neill, Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo, Paul Robeson, and many others. Also found are period photographs of Charleston, South Carolina and Harlem street scenes.
95 letters from Rachel Field, 75 letters from Langston Hughes, 3 letters from Armin Landeck, 46 letters from Josephine Pinckney, 1 letter from Gertrude Stein, 7 letters from Alice B. Toklas, 1 postcard from Mark Van Doren, and 25 letters from Carl Van Vechten are photocopies. Originals of the Hughes and Toklas letters are located at the Yale University Library. Location of the remaining original letters are unknown.
The Prentiss Taylor papers offer researchers insight into the rich cultural documentation of the Harlem Renaissance and the development of twentieth-century printmaking as an American fine art.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into ten series. The largest series housing Subject Files is arranged alphabetically, primarily by name of correspondent, maintaining Taylor's original arrangement. The remaining series are arranged in chronological order. Oversized material from various series has been housed in Box 21 (Sol) and OV 22 and is noted in the Series Description/Container Listing Section at the appropriate folder title with see also/see references.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1918-1985, undated (Box 1; 6 folders)
Series 2: Miscellaneous Receipts, 1929-1986, undated (Box 1; 11 folders)
Series 3: Insurance Records, 1960-1976 (Box 1; 1 folder)
Series 4: Notes, 1921-1984, undated (Box 1; 18 folders)
Series 5: Writings, 1924-1971, undated (Box 1-2; 51 folders)
Series 6: Art Work, 1916-1975, undated (Box 2; 14 folders)
Series 7: Scrapbooks, 1885-1956 (Box 2, 21; 10 folders)
Series 8: Printed Material, 1914-1990, undated (Box 2-3, 21; 29 folders)
Series 9: Photographs, 1908-1984, undated (Box 3, 21; 0.7 linear feet)
Series 10: Subject Files, 1885-1991, undated (Box 3-21, OV 22; 18.0 linear feet)
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms. People, families and organizations are listed under "Subjects" when they are the topic of collection contents and under "Names" when they are creators or contributors.
Subjects:
Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967; Hurston, Zora Neale; Kahlo, Frida; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953; Rivera, Diego, 1886-1957; Robeson, Paul, 1898-1976; Robinson, Bill, 1878-1949; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964; American University (Washington, D.C.) -- Fine Arts Dept. -- Faculty; Golden Stair Press; Society of Washington Printmakers (Washington, D.C.)
Subjects-Topical:
Art teachers -- Washington (D.C.); Art therapy; Harlem Renaissance; Lithography -- 20th century -- Washington (D.C.); Lithographers -- Washington (D.C.); Painters -- Washington (D.C.); Printmakers -- Washington (D.C.)
Types of Materials:
Drawings; Photographs; Prints; Sound recordings; Sketchbooks; Scrapbooks; Writings
Names:
Field, Rachel, 1894-1942; Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967; Landeck, Armin, 1905-; Pinckney, Josephine, 1895-1957; Stein, Gertrude, 1874-1946; Toklas, Alice B.; Van Doren, Mark, 1894-1972; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964
Provenance
The Prentiss Taylor papers were donated in 1978 and 1984 by Taylor, and in 1992 and 2004 by his companion, Roderick S. Quiroz, for the estate of Prentiss Taylor. The material lent by Taylor for microfilming in 1978 on reel 1392 was not included as a later gift, and is not described in this finding aid. The collection contains photocopies of letters from Langston Hughes and Alice B. Toklas that Lawrence donated to Yale University Library.
Restrictions on Access
The collection has been digitized and is available online via AAA's website.
Existence/Location of Originals
95 letters from Rachel Field, 75 letters from Langston Hughes, 3 letters from Armin Landeck, 46 letters from Josephine Pinckney, 1 letter from Gertrude Stein, 7 letters from Alice B. Toklas, 1 postcard from Mark Van Doren, and 25 letters from Carl Van Vechten are photocopies. Originals of the Hughes and Toklas letters are located at the Yale University Library. Location of the remaining original letters are unknown.
Related Material
Prentiss Taylor papers are also located at the Yale University Library.
Separated Material
Three notebooks detailing Taylor's lithographs; a gift and sale notebook; a guestbook; exhibition announcements; and a brochure were loaned to the Archives of American Art by Taylor in 1978 for microfilming on reel 1392. These materials are not described in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms Available
The collection was digitized from microfilm in 2008 and is available via the Archives of American Art's website. Researchers should note that the legibility of some materials is poor due to the microfilm quality; researchers may wish to request reels 5911-5935 through interlibrary loan.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1918-1985, undated, Series 1:; (Box 1; 6 folders; Reel 5911)
  Biographical material consists of school-related material, membership cards, biographical accounts, and job application forms including letters of recommendation.
  - Scholarship Certificate, Report Card, and Graduation Announcement, 1918-1924 (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 13-16)
  - Yearbook, 1923 (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 18-58)
  - Yearbook, 1924 (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 61-101)
  - Membership Cards, 1933-1984, undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 104-105)
  - Biographical Accounts, 1954-1985, undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 107-130)
  - Job Applications, 1942-1948 (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 132-162)
- Miscellaneous Receipts, 1929-1986, undated, Series 2:; (Box 1; 11 folders; Reel 5911)
  This series consists of receipts for art supplies, books, and art-related services.
  - Miscellaneous Receipts, 1929-1986, undated, (11 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 164-545)
- Insurance Records, 1960-1976, Series 3:; (Box 1; 1 folder; Reel 5911)
  This series consists of an insurance policy, receipt, and a damage claim from the shipment of art work.
  - Insurance Records, 1960-1976 (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 547-565)
- Notes, 1921-1984, undated, Series 4:; (Box 1; 18 folders; Reel 5911)
  This series includes lists of artists, art works, and exhibitions, information about travel, and notes on cemetery epitaphs.
  - Notebook of Theater Performances and Concerts, 1923-1954 (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 568-653)
  - Notebook of Artists and Their Works, undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 655-686)
  - Card File of Artists, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 688-700)
  - Lists of Art Works, 1951-1982 (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 702-741)
  - Lists of Exhibitions, 1966-1977 (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 743-753)
  - List of Photographs, undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 755-765)
  - Notes for Trip to Mexico, 1962 (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 767-775)
  - Notes for Trip to England, Spain, and Italy, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 777-787)
  - Notes for Trip to England, France, and Italy, 1963-1966, (3 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 789-910)
  - Card File "Invitations 1966," 1966 (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 912-915)
  - List of WPA Artists, 1984 (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 917-923)
  - Group Progress Notes, 1975 (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 925-929)
  - Notes on Cemetery Epitaphs, undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 931-969)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1921-1978, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 971-1029)
- Writings, 1924-1971, undated, Series 5:; (Box 1-2; 51 folders; Reels 5911-5912)
  Writings include a hand-made book Modelling Zorach P.M. that contains annotations and photographs of Taylor and William Zorach's sculpture class. Also included are manuscripts on miscellaneous art-related topics, poems, and reviews written by Taylor about other artists' work. All writings are by Taylor except for a script by Henry Siddons and a poem by Joseph Titzell.
  - Hand-Made Book Modelling Zorach P.M., 1932-1934 (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1031-1069)
  - Untitled Manuscript about Arnold Davis, undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1071-1078)
  - Untitled Manuscript about "Charleston Negroes," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1080-1081)
  - Untitled Typescript about Elocution, undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1083-1085)
  - Untitled Manuscript about a Hospital Stay, undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1087-1090)
  - Untitled Typescript about Italian Marionette Theater, undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1092-1097)
  - Manuscript "American Printmaking," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1099-1116)
  - Script "Aucassin and Nicolette," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1118-1128)
  - Script "Ballet of a Sunday Picnic," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1130-1137)
  - Manuscript "The Candystriped Blouse," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1139-1147)
  - Typescript "Characteristics of Current American Prints," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1149-1200)
  - Typescript "Foreword" Concerning Library of Congress Pennell Competition, undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1202-1208)
  - Manuscript and Typescript "How Art Therapy May Help Reintegrate the Disordered Mind," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1210-1227)
  - Typescript "James Monroe," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1229-1231)
  - Manuscript "A Particular Aspect," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1233-1250)
  - Typescript "Photography and Its Great Tradition," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1252-1255)
  - Manuscript and Typescript "Preludes to Finland," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1257-1260)
  - Manuscript "Nellie and Abby Putnam," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1262-1294)
  - Typescript "Return, O Holy Dove," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1296-1308)
  - Typescript "Some Humanitarian Printmakers," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1310-1412)
  - Script "Susanna and the Elders," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1414-1418)
  - Typescript "Three Sentences on Art in Washington," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1420-1421)
  - Typescript "To Paint American," undated (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1423-1438)
  - Typescript "Scenery and Costumes," 1924 (Box 1, Reel 5911, Frame 1440-1447)
  - Typescript "Figurehead," 1928 (Box 1, Reel 5912, Frame 14-68)
  - Script "Trolleys," 1928 (Box 1, Reel 5912, Frame 70-84)
  - Typescript "The American Artist and Our Plain Man's Renaissance," 1942 (Box 1, Reel 5912, Frame 86-98)
  - Typescript, Letters, and Notes for "Pissaro: Patriarch of Impressionism," 1941-1947, (3 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5912, Frame 100-240)
  - Manuscript, Typescript, and Letters for "Cezanne," 1947-1948, (4 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5912, Frame 242-546)
  - Manuscript, Typescript, and Notes for "Degas," 1949-1950, (5 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 549-815)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1971, undated (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 817-828)
  - Miscellaneous Poems, 1925-1933, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 830-891)
  - Notebook of Book Reviews, 1938-1940 (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 893-930)
  - Miscellaneous Book Reviews, 1938-1942, (3 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 932-1017)
  - A Review of Three Plays and a Book, 1940 (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 1019-1026)
  - Exhibition Reviews by Taylor, 1937-1939, (2 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 1028-1105)
  - Script "The Sicilian Romance" by Henry Siddons, undated (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 1107-1146)
  - Illustrated Poems by Joseph Titzell, 1927 (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 1148-1163)
- Art Work, 1916-1975, undated, Series 6:; (Box 2; 14 folders; Reels 5912-5913)
  This series consists of one folder of Taylor's drawings, 14 sketchbooks, designs for bookplates, etchings, and silkscreen prints.
  - Drawings, 1916-1925, undated (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 1166-1171)
  - Sketchbook 1, 1963 (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 1174-1195)
  - Sketchbook 2, 1965 (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 1197-1224)
  - Sketchbook 3, 1965 (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 1226-1246)
  - Sketchbook 4, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 1248-1272)
  - Sketchbook 5, 1966 (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 1274-1286)
  - Sketchbook 6, 1966 (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 1288-1311)
  - Sketchbook 7, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 1313-1336)
  - Sketchbook 8, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 1338-1361)
  - Sketchbook 9, 1968 (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 1363-1385)
  - Sketchbook 10, 1968 (Box 2, Reel 5912, Frame 1387-1413)
  - Sketchbook 11, 1968 (Box 2, Reel 5913, Frame 14-30)
  - Sketchbook 12, 1969 (Box 2, Reel 5913, Frame 32-56)
  - Sketchbook 13, 1973 (Box 2, Reel 5913, Frame 58-66)
  - Sketchbook 14, 1975 (Box 2, Reel 5913, Frame 68-83)
  - Bookplate Designs, undated (Box 2, Reel 5913, Frame 85-88)
  - Prints, 1926, undated, (3 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5913, Frame 90-124)
- Scrapbooks, 1885-1956, Series 7:; (Box 2, 21; 10 folders; Reel 5913)
  The Scrapbooks series consists of one volume of clippings, and another containing letters, exhibition catalogs, and miscellaneous printed material.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1885-1956, (9 folders; includes oversized materials from Box 21) (Box 2, Reel 5913, Frame 127-305)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1921-1937 (Box 2, Reel 5913, Frame 307-371)
  - Oversized Pages for Scrapbook 1, (scanned with box 2, reel 5913, frames 127-305) (Box 21 (sol), Reel 5913)
- Printed Material, 1914-1990, undated, Series 8:; (Box 2-3, 21; 29 folders; Reel 5913)
  This series includes clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, programs primarily for theatrical productions, bulletins, and miscellaneous printed material.
  - Clippings, 1923-1990, undated, (18 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5913, Frame 374-702)
  - Clippings about African-Americans, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Reel 5913, Frame 704-748)
  - Clippings about the Washington, D.C. Area, 1977-1985 (Box 2, Reel 5913, Frame 750-769)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Taylor, 1942-1990, (Includes oversized materials from Box 21) (Box 2, Reel 5913, Frame 771-796)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Others, 1954-1975 (Box 2, Reel 5913, Frame 798-803)
  - Reproductions of Art Work, 1935, undated (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 807-815)
  - Miscellaneous Programs, 1917-1927, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 817-872)
  - Bulletins of the Children of the American Revolution, 1914-1922 (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 874-893)
  - Bulletins of the Washington Leica Club, 1936 (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 895-901)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1930, undated (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 903-914)
  - Oversized Exhibition Announcement for Taylor, 1963, (scanned with box 2, reel 5913, frames 771-796) (Box 21 (sol), Reel 5913)
- Photographs, 1908-1984, undated, Series 9:; (Box 3, 21; 0.6 linear feet; Reel 5913)
  This series primarily consists of three albums containing photographs of family members, friends, and colleagues. Album 1 contains photographs of Taylor, and friends singer Gladys Bentley, composers Celius Dougherty and Nora Holt, dancer Bill Robinson, and author Gerald Sykes. Some of the photographs are by Carl Van Vechten. Album 2 contains photographs of Mrs. John White Alexander, sculptor Richmond Barth, artists Henri Brenner, William Calfee, Margaret Casey Gates, Robert Franklin Gates, Anne Goldthwaite, Armen Landeck, George Miller, and H. L. Wade White, authors Laura Bent, Douglas Stites Fairchild, Rachel Field, Irving Fineman, Frances Frost, Langston Hughes, Clements and Katharine Ball Ripley, Chard Powers Smith, and Mark Van Doren, playwright Zora Neale Hurston, Broadway composer Max Ewing, actress and philanthropist Libby Holman Reynolds, and puppeteers Florence and Remo Bufano.
  Album 3 contains additional photographs of the subjects found in Album 2, as well as photographs of Taylor, his friends, nude models, and views of various towns and locations on the East Coast from South Carolina, to Harlem, to Maine. The contents of photograph albums 2 and 3 are arranged alphabetically. Also included in this series are miscellaneous photographs of Taylor, his works, works by others, and travel photographs of New York City, the American West, and various destinations primarily in the United States. Miscellaneous photographs include cemetery headstones and views at a race course.
  - Album 1, 1908-1936, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 917-960)
  - Album 2, 1932-1938, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 962-982)
  - Album 3, 1929-1939, undated (Box 21 (sol), Reel 5913, Frame 984-1116)
  - Photographs of Prentiss Taylor, 1910-1977, (5 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 1118-1154)
  - Photographs of Costume Designs by Taylor, undated (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 1156-1164)
  - Photographs of Still Life Compositions, undated (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 1166-1167)
  - Photographs of Art Work by Taylor, undated (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 1169-1181)
  - Photographs of Mural at R. F. Flint's in New Haven, 1940 (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 1183-1187)
  - Photographs of Art Work by Others, 1977, undated (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 1189-1195)
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Friends, 1928-1977, undated, (5 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 1197-1213)
  - Photographs of Travel, 1932-1984, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 1215-1244)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, 1932-1977, undated (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 1246-1251)
- Subject Files, 1885-1991, undated, Series 10:; (Box 3-21, OV 22; 18.0 linear feet; Reels 5913-5935)
  The Subject Files series reflects the names of individuals and organizations with which Taylor was associated throughout his career. Each file may contain correspondence between the subject and Taylor, as well as related printed material and photographs.
  - Miscellaneous Unidentified Subjects, 1951-1986, undated (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 1254-1287)
  - Subject Files without Surnames, 1927-1986, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5913, Frame 1289-1415)
  - Subject Files without Surnames, 1927-1986, (4 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5914, Frame 14-131)
  - A & M Leatherlines, Inc., 1978 (Box 3, Reel 5914, Frame 134)
  - Yuji Abe (Yoseido Gallery), 1961-1962 (Box 3, Reel 5914, Frame 136-145)
  - Berenice Abbott, 1976 (Box 3, Reel 5914, Frame 147)
  - Abbott School of Fine and Commercial Art, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Reel 5914, Frame 149-151)
  - Alice Acheson, 1950-1983 (Box 3, Reel 5914, Frame 153-166)
  - William B. Acker, 1974 (Box 3, Reel 5914, Frame 168)
  - Robert R. Adam, 1945-1968, (3 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5914, Frame 170-292)
  - Clinton Adams, 1990 (Box 3, Reel 5914, Frame 294-296)
  - Grace Adams, 1935 (Box 3, Reel 5914, Frame 298-299)
  - Minna Adams, 1938 (Box 3, Reel 5914, Frame 301-302)
  - Alonzo Aden (Barnett Aden Gallery), 1961 (Box 3, Reel 5914, Frame 304-306)
  - Elmer Adler, 1932-1962 (Box 3, Reel 5914, Frame 308-313)